<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-03T16:54:08-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Biogeography and Macroecology 2022</title><author><name>Biogeography and Macroecology 2022</name></author><entry><title type="html">Biogeography in R workshop</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/updates/00_Biogeography-R-workshop-announcement/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Biogeography in R workshop" /><published>2021-10-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-10-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/updates/00_Biogeography-R-workshop-announcement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/updates/00_Biogeography-R-workshop-announcement/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;biogeography-in-r-workshop&quot;&gt;Biogeography in R workshop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the maiden edition of a workshop in biogeographic methods and tools development in the R computing environment. The course will take place at &lt;a href=&quot;https://tamucc.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Texas A&amp;amp;M University-Corpus Christi&lt;/a&gt; from January 10-15, 2022. The workshop is intended for anyone with interest in biogeographic methods and little prior computer programming experience, to an intermediate or advanced computational biologist curious about honing their skills in R for biogeography and macroecology. Selected participants will be encouraged to arrive with a dataset of their own, or with an idea for a biogeographic project in R.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first 3 days of the workshop, course leaders will provide an introduction to the primary data structures and methods of common biogeographic R packages, good R practices, basics of computational algorithms for biogeography, and an overview of other essential topics of software development in R. Over the next 3 workshop days, participants will work in breakout groups with workshop leaders to develop a biogeographic project in R or develop a small R package on their chosen topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop is funded by an NSF award to Dr. Barnabas Daru (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=2113424&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;NSF DBI-2113424&lt;/a&gt;), with additional support from Texas A&amp;amp;M University-Corpus Christi (TAMUCC). All accepted students originating from a U.S. port of origin will have their travel costs covered or defrayed, and room and board during the workshop will be provided. As the workshop will be held on the beautiful island campus of TAMUCC, accommodation is comfortable as participants will be stationed in their own bedroom but with shared bathroom with another participant. To expand access and participation, the lectures from these workshops will be webcast for other interested parties to participate. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;All participants are expected to follow CDC and Texas A&amp;amp;M University-Corpus Christi’s COVID-19 safety protocols – participants are encouraged to wear a mask and social distance at all times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tamucc.edu/campus-guide/index.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;more information on COVID-19 campus guide is available here &lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tamucc.co1.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_4YOcN3cvPh1iSeW&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--large btn--success btn--block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Apply for the course here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admission is competitive. Applications should be submitted by &lt;strong&gt;November 1, 2021&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Barnabas Daru</name><email>darunabas@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Updates" /><category term="link" /><category term="Post Formats" /><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/TAMUCC.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/TAMUCC.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>